<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Newspaper, Reading in Longitudinal Perspective: Beyond Structural Constraints</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Chaffee</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sun</forename><forename type="middle">Yuel</forename><surname>Choe</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jeanne</forename><surname>Penroac</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">Waver</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Richard</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Donald</forename><surname>Cole</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Shaw</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Chaffcc</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jackson-Beck</forename><forename type="middle">Jean</forename><surname>Marilyn</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><surname>Durall</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Newspaper, Reading in Longitudinal Perspective: Beyond Structural Constraints</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">8268CAF519047665A2937AD48736F5CC</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-09-21T12:21+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Transitional constraints in lives period of historical decline, readership of individuals and beyond control studies still find that there are many more of the newspaper affect whether readers than non-readers among adult Americans.' Reading a daily newspaper is a stronger norm than, say, voting, person becomes reader. b Although newspaper reading is in a although less universal than watching tele-1 John P. Robinson and Leo W. Jeffres. 'The Chsnging Role vision Or driving a car. The sizable (and of Newspapers in the A ~C of Television," /ourna/ism Mono-growing) minority who have nof adopted graph No. 63 (September. 1979). pp. 2-3. lup. -A Scientific Method for Dctermln~ng Reader I ~~~~~~~, . . JOURhALlSM QUARTERLY. 7:128-41 (June. 1930). this norm have been the focus of continuas a concerned newspaper industry.2 Readnon-readers at the lower end of the socioeconomic ladder; lack Of resources and cognitive skills due to low education, and lack Of and leisure time are strong correlates of non-reading3 Among the earliest quantitative studio of masscommunication phenomena were rcadcrbhip surveys. such as George Gal-</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Such static explanations, based on cross-sectional surveys, stress a conception of newspaper reading and non-reading as stable, habitual behaviors grounded in the social structure. There is indeed evidence that, for many adult Americans, media use patterns are stable habits to which they have been socialized from childhood.' Youngsters in families of high socioeconomic status learn to use mass media quite differently from those in disadvantaged homes, in particular being less likely to adopt newspaper reading.3</p><p>But, for many, newspaper reading is not a persistent, stable behavior throughout one's lifetime. As Tipton points out, there are "chronic" non-readers who are unlikely ever to take up the newspaper, but there are also many people who "sometimes" ,Steven H. Chaffee is director of the School of Journalism and Mass Communication at Wisconsin-Madison where Sun Yucl Choe is a doctoral candidate. 20 1 read newspapers.6 Periodic fluctuation between reading and non-reading cannot be explained by stable individual differences growing out of socio-economic disadvantage. Understanding behavioral changes in newspaper reading requires more dynamic explanations than those implied by theories based on social stratification. The decline in the newspaper audience in recent decades has after all occurred despite the fact that educational levels in the U.S. population have steadily risen, effectively removing the principal structural constraint against reading for most people. <ref type="bibr">'</ref> The decisive behavior at stake is the dynamic process of acquiring or discontinuing the habit of daily newspaper reading, not the static condition of maintaining a habit of reading or nonreading.</p><p>The purpose of this paper, then, is to go beyond stable structural factors in a search for explanations of changes in newspaper reading behavior. Our basic assumption is that reading a daily newspaper is a communication behavior that entails some costs and is limited by constraints operating within as well as upon the person. While we would not minimize systemic constraints, such as the relative unavailability of newspapers in developing countries,8 we are mainly concerned here with individuallevel factors that constrain a person from reading newspapers even in a country where they are highly available at very low cost. We also assume that the factors that explain change are different from those that explain the persistence of stable habits. Consequently, we will examine panel data, which will allow us to analyze newspaper reading in longitudinal perspective rather than simply in terms of static correlates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Varieties of Constraint</head><p>We propose that there are three major types of constraints affecting newspaper reading. First and most pervasive are structural constraints such as we have discussed above. We call these "structural" because they are determined largely by the person's disadvantageous location in the social structure and are generally beyond</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Q U A R T E R L Y</formula><p>his personal control. Many among the poor, the elderly, the isolated and the undereducated may never surpass these constraints and so should be expected to remain nonreaders across the years.</p><p>But, while structural constraints may be sufficient to explain non-reading, their absence is obviously not sufficient to account for reading. People who are free from structural constraints may nevertheless find that transitional constraints due to personal life-cycle changes disrupt their newspaper reading habits. Although they are well-educated, today's young adults are especially likely to undergo many transitions such as changes in residence, or in marital or parental status, occupational changes like completing schooling or losing a job, and other'life-cycle passages. To the extent that newspaper reading is integrated into one's daily habits, we should expect it to be disrupted by at least some of these transitions.</p><p>The importance of transitional constraints has been stressed by studies that focus on mobile young adults as potential newspaper subscribers.9 But, we assume here that, because newspaper subscription is especially sensitive to changes in residence and other basic elements of one's living situation, changes in personal status will be associated with change in two directions, both from non-reading to reading and vice versa. The emphasis in the research literature on structural correlates, and the general failure to distinguish theoretically between the different roles played by transitional and structural factors, are largely due to the lack of longitudinal studies in which changes could be examined separately from stable habits.</p><p>A third set of constraints can account for the direction of change, from or toward habitual newspaper reading. We will call these self-constraints. because they are to a considerable extent exercised by the person himself, on the basis of his interest in the services the newspaper provides. Newspapers publish a wide variety of content.</p><p>.A reader should presumably be attracted to at least some of that material; one who is not is a potential non-reader, who might well respond to a life-cycle transition by dropping the newspaper. Cross-sectional studies have found that interest and participation in community and political activities are rather strong correlates of newspaper reading. 10 Self-constraints are dispositional in nature, stable individual differences in interest that should become manifest at points of transition in one's life. That is, just as we find stable readers more interested in political and community news than stable non-readers, we should also find those who change from non-reading to reading at a transition point more interested than those who change in the opposite direction.</p><p>Although we are using the rather negative term "constraints" to refer to a person's lack of interest in news, it is obvious that there is also a positive, motivational element of attraction to newspaper content which is equally important in explaining reading." Both the attraction and the constraint components of self-constraints can be traced to structural and transitional antecedents. A person who for structural reasons has not been well educated, for example, may lack the base of information necessary to comprehend current events in the press. Or, someone who has lived many years in one community may have built up a considerable interest in local activities and personalities; the absence of transitional constraint indirectly accounts for his attraction to the newspaper. But, selfconstraints are to a degree under the person's c o n t r o l , whereas s t r u c t u r a l constraints are largely beyond the person's control and transitional constraints involve concerns that for the person overshadow the relatively minor matter of newspaper use.</p><p>We view self-constraint as tertiary in comparison with other factors. Whether a person is interested enough in press content to read a daily newspaper is a question that may never arise for people who are structurally constrained and is not the operative issue for those who find themselves temporarily beset with transitional constraints. Self-constraints should manifest themselves more strongly in relation to the amount of newspaper reading, to what is read, and to the attention given to similar content in other media, than to the simple question of whether or not one reads a daily newspaper at all.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Theoretical Relationships</head><p>Our theoretical structure, outlined in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>, should not be mistaken for a simple linear model in which each constraint is a n independent variable contributing to a unidirnensional dependent variable, newspaper reading. The three types of constraint are inter-related, and their total effect is to differentiate the p o p ulation into different groups of people in terms of readership status.</p><p>As Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> suggests, structural constraints are considered prior to other factors in our model. Not only d o they have direct effects on readership status, accounting for chronic non-reading, but also they affect the other types of constraint. For example, the economically and culturally disadvantaged are probably more subject than other people to such transitional constraints as changes in employment status. They are less able to </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CONSTRAINTS</head><p>take an active role in politics and public affairs, which in turn ought to reduce their interest in political news.'* Transitional disruptions can have a similar, if more temporary, negative impact on political activity. What might appear in correlational analyses to be direct effects of dispositional self-constraints could prove instead to be indirect effects of structural or transitional constraints. The pervasiveness of structural constraints, in terms of theoretical priority, should nevertheless not overshadow the independent conceptual significance of transitional and self-constraints in explaining newspaper readership status.</p><p>The main focus of this paper is on changes in readership status. Why, over time, d o some people drop the newspaper reading habit while others take it up? In the terms of our model, d o different kinds of constraints operate on people who exhibit these opposing patterns of change? To address such questions, we need to compare four different readership status groups.</p><p>The first group, which should be accounted for by structural constraints, would be stable non-readers, who over time persist in nor reading a daily newspaper because of chronic deficits that can be traced t o lack of education, income, and the like. Among the remainder who are not structurally constrained, stable readers need to be distinguished from groups that are unstable in readership status. Stable readers, i.e. those who over time continue to be habitual newspaper readers, should be relatively free of both transitional and self-constraints.</p><p>The two unstable groups should be differentiated from the two stable groups mainly by transitional constraints. That is, we expect transitional constraints to be associated with changes both to and away from newspaper reading. The difference between the two unstable groups should reside in self-constraints. When the person experiences a life-cycle transition that disrupts his daily habits in general, we should expect change in readership status; change from reading to non-reading ("dropping" the newspaper) should be associated with self-constraints, while those who change in the opposite direction ("adders") should not be self-constrained people.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design and Measures</head><p>Our study is a secondary analysis of data from a national panel survey by the Center for Political Studies (CPS) of the University of Michigan during the election campaigns of <ref type="bibr">1974 and 1976.13</ref>   Over the two-year period, the unstable adder and dropper groups are much smaller than the stable groups (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">1</ref>); because of the large total sample, even the smallest group (droppers, N=66) is large enough to provide reasonably reliable statistical estimates. This panel probably underestimates the incidence of droppers in the total popu1ation.I' Separating 14Thc CPS 1974-1976panel is not as accuratcareprcscntation of the U.S. adult population as would bc either of the crosssectional samples drawn in 1974 and 1976. Attrition from a panel over time is non-random. with people who move from one residence to another k i n g particularly likely to drop out. One consequence of this is that the percentage of newspaper readers would appear from Table <ref type="table">I</ref>  '&amp;Some qucrljonr were asked in 1974 only of those who fin1 said they rcad a daily newspaper. whcrus in 1976 thesc q u a -Lions were asked of all respondents. Other questions were asked in only one year, or were asked with different wording or in different questionnaire contexts. These variations introduce somt minor elements of nonsomparability into our data annlysis.</p><p>adders from droppers is essential to testing our model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Structural constraints.</head><p>Operational indicators of structural constraints are education and income. Education is the highest year the respondent completed in school (converted to a 10-point scale). Income is total income of the respondent's family (on a 20-point scale).</p><p>Transirional constraints. To locate lifecycie changes and instabilities, we created a number of dummy variables. Three of these represented change from 1974 to 1976 in residential, marital and occupational status. All three were scored 0 if there was no change and 1 if there was change in any direction. For example, change from married to divorced or viceversa would both be scored 1. This follows our theoretical assumption that it is change itself, not the direction of change, that accounts for unstable newspaper reading.</p><p>Our other indicator of transitional constraints was the person's stage in the life cycle. In general we assume (see above) that younger adults experience more lifecycle transitions than older people, even aside from the three specific types of transition we could measure with these data (see previous paragraph). But we also assume that the functions of age are not linear across the entire life-span.15 So we created two dummy variables, one representing age under 35 years and the second, age 65 or older <ref type="bibr">(in 1976)</ref>. This in effect trichotomizes the sample into three life-cycle groups that should be progressively less likely to experience transitional constraints Self-constraints. Optimally, in a thorough study of self-constraints, we would have a wide range of measures of newspaper reading motivations, the absence of which would function as self-constraints. These would include the many kinds of involvement in political and community affairs that previous research has indicated correlate strongly with newspaper use. In secondary analysis of the CPS election studies, however, we are mostly limited to measures of political involvement, with an emphasis on the immediate election campaign. I6 While these measures represent only a subset of the potential bases for self-constraint. they are strong correlates not only of reading vs. non-reading but also of adding vs. dropping the newspaper.I7 We created four scales to represent campaign interest, campaign activity, attention to public affairs, and political activity outside the campaign context.</p><p>Campaign interest was the sum of two five-point scales, indicating how much the person cared about the election (1974) and how interested the person was in the campaign <ref type="bibr">(1976)</ref>. Campaign activity was a sum score for 1974 and 1976 combined, based on the person's report of four kinds of participation in the fall election campaign. Attention to public affairs was the sum of I974 and 1976 self-reported general attention scores.I* Political activity was a sum of scores based on reports in 1976 of six local and five national-level forms of political participation that were not specific to the election campaign context.19 Newspaper content use. Respondents who said they read a daily newspaper, which included the droppers in 1974 and the adders in 1976, were then asked the frequency with which they read various types of articles. To test our hypothesis that content preferences within a medium would be a function of self-constraints, we created separate summed indices of the frequency of reading of "hard news" and "soft news."20</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Plan for Analysis</head><p>On the basis of our theoretical model, we would expect the four readership groups to differ systematically in structural, transitional and self-constraints. The most demanding test of this overall model would be a single multivariate analysis that examines differences among all four groups on all our indicators of constraint. For this purpose we will use a multiple discriminant analysis.*'</p><p>The indicators of self-constraint based on reading of "hard news" and "soft news" cannot be entered in this four-group analysis, because questions about newspaper reading were not asked of those who said they did not read a daily paper. Specific analyses of these measures will be per-formed separately from the main analysis for those groups that were asked questions about different kinds of newspaper content.</p><p>Operationally, our hypotheses predict that stable non-readers will be much more constrained than other groups by the structural factors, education and income. The two unstable groups should be more subject than the two stable groups are to transitional constraints, including changes in residential, occupational and marital status as well as the more global indicator of being in the youthful phase of the life cycle.</p><p>Self-constraints should, following our model in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>, be empirically associated with structural constraints, to which they are partially attributable. Theoretically, however, we view self-constraints as determining use of the newspaper among those who are not structurally constrained. Measures of political involvement, and associated reading of "hard" news, should be important factors among people who are readers at a given time, differentiating the self-constrained droppers from stable readers and adders. We would not predict differences among these three groups in consumption of "soft" news, to which politically oriented self-constraints would *'Hard news" consisted of stories about international news. national politics, and slate and loul politics T o f t news" consisted of stories about people in the community. home and garden. and crime and a m d c n u . Responses were scored I=ncvcr. 2:rarcly. 3=sometimes and 4=frequently. in responseto the quation, "How often d o you read newspaper s t o r k about...?" The means in Tables <ref type="table">5</ref> and<ref type="table" target="#tab_14">6</ref> represent the summed scores across the three items for each index.  not apply. More generally, we see selfconstraints as determining the amount and kinds of newspaper content one reads, whereas structural and transitional constraints have more to do with whether one reads a newspaper at all. Our emphasis on constraints that limit newspaper reading implies that we d o not assume that competition from other mass media is a major explanatory factor. This accords with recent research that stresses the complementary, rather than competitive, role of media in people's lives.22 We d o assume, though, that constraints of the types we have outlined could operate on use of other media besides the newspaper.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Descriptive statistics for each of the indicators of constraints are shown for the four groups in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">2</ref>. N o univariate tests of group differences are reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">2</ref>, because our hypotheses predict complex multivariate patterns of group differences rather than simply predicting that the groups will differ on a particular variable. Because of the large sample size, the groups d o indeed differ significantly on almost all of the variables shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">2</ref>. each variable and each function, rotated using a varimax criterion. Variables are listed in the table according to the function with which each correlates most strongly, and the strength of that correlation. The second set of coefficients shows standardized discriminant functions (also varimax rotation), the interpretation of which is analogous to that of beta weights in multiple regression. The largest correlation for each variable by function has been outlined by a box to facilitate interpretation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Multiple discriminant analysis. All the variables that appear in</head><p>The significant first two functions lend rather strong support to our conceptual distinction between structural and transitional constraints. Function 1 can be interpreted as a combined structural/self-constraints dimension, with education a very important factor and income a secondary one. The political involvement measures indicating self-constraints also correlate with Function 1, although they are not so specific to that function as are education and income. This correlation of selfconstraints with the antecedent structural constraints was expected (Figure <ref type="figure">I</ref>). The standardized discriminant function coefficients for the political involvement measures are not nearly so strong for Function 1 as are the correlations; this indicates that much of the commonality between Function 1 and self-constraints is accounted for by education and income. As one might expect of a factor so pervasive as we have suggested structural constraints are, Function 1 explains the largest proportion of the total variance (16%) among the four groups.</p><p>The second significant function seems to represent transitional constraints, or at least those associated with youth and mobility. The strongest component in Function 2 is the dummy variable representing the early years of the adult life cycle (age under 35). Change in residence, a transition that almost inevitably disrupts newspaper subscription, is a factor of secondary importance in Function 2. This function accounts for 4% of the total variance among groups.</p><p>Although not statistically significant. Function 3 suggests that two other transitional factors, change in marital or employment status, could have distinctive effects on newspaper reading. These two life-cycle transitions, while strongly asso- ciated with the third function, are virtually unrelated to the first two functions. Self- constraint indicators specific to the election campaign are also associated with Function 3. This might mean that changes in employment and marital status are transitional constraints that lead immediately to self-constraints such as depressed political involvement. These transitions, which often involve leaving married or employed status, are not especially associated with any one age group. Such interpretations are quite speculative, however; we should not make much of a non-significant dimension.</p><p>The mean for each reading group on each function (group centroids) is shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_12">4</ref>; the entries in this table are standard scores. As predicted, the first function, representing structural a n d selfconstraints, mainly discriminates between the non-readers and the other three groups. The stable readers are also somewhat higher on Function 1 than are the two unstable groups, adders and droppers. The second function, whicii mainly involves life-cycle transitional constraints, discriminates as hypothesized between the unstable groups (adders and droppers) and the stable ones (readers and non-readers).</p><p>The operation of self-constraints, which are associated empirically with the prior structural and transitional constraints, does not emerge clearly from the multiple for simplicity here we lump together as "soft news." The net effect of self-constraints overall, then, would be to reduce a person's total use of the newspaper.</p><p>Our main interest is in the interaction between type of reader and type of news read. The model predicts such an interaction when comparing droppers to readers but not when comparing adders to readers, because only droppers should be selfconstrained. Treating hard w. soft news content M repeated measures in analysis of variance provides us a sensitive test of this interaction.</p><p>Table <ref type="table">5</ref> compares the hard and soft news reading in 1974 of the two groups that ropbrted daily newspaper reading at that time, the stable readers and the droppers.</p><p>The groupbyantent interaction is significant and COMiSteUt with our prediction in that the hard news score for droppers is much lower than any other cell means.</p><p>There is also a rignificant group difference, the stable readers reporting more frequent reading of both types of news. Table <ref type="table">5</ref> further shows a significant main effect of content, the mean for soft news being somewhat higher than for hard news due to low hard-news reading among the droppers. This content "effect" should be considered an artifact of the significant interaction.</p><p>By contrast, there is no group-bycontent interaction in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_14">6</ref>, where the 1976 figures for the same measures are analyzed for the two groups who reported reading newspapers in 1976, adders and stable readers. The stable readers are significantly more frequent readers of all types of news stories than are the adders, as was the case for the reader-dropper comparison in Table <ref type="table">5</ref>. But, as we hypothesized, there is no tendency for either group to exhibit self-constraints that would specifically reduce hard-news reading. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_14">6</ref> shows no difference between hard and soft news reading overall, nor within either group.</p><p>The adders and droppers cannot be compared directly in hard vs. soft news reading. because their content-specific measures had to be taken in different years. The droppers, whose discontinuance of newspaper reading was hypothesized to be a function of self-constraints, clearly diverge from the other groups by their low consumption of hard news content.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Summary</head><p>Overall. our constraints model has held up quite well under empirical test. As we predicted, structural constraints account for stable non-reading. Transitional constraints, particularly those associated with youth and mobility, predict changes in readership status, non-directionally. Directional changes, as represented by the adders and droppers, are associated mainly with indicators of self-constraint, based on lack of interest and involvement in the kinds of political affairs that are heavily covered by newspapers. The data are also consistent with our expectation that self-constraints would be a function of structural factors, which are the most pervasive constraints determining readership status.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>A major implication of this study is the conclusion that lost newspaper readership, the industry's most vexing long-term problem, is not directly attributable todeficiencies in the newspaper itself. Newspapers of superior reportorial quality may earn somewhat higher net circulation figures.'J But, for many people, readership status is heavily constrained by factors beyond the control of the individual-or of the newspaper. Social change, such as increased mobility or marital instability, may well be as important in determining the future of the newspaper in American life as will the press's performance in the media marketplace.</p><p>Attempts to maintain readership by making the newspaper more like television and other entertainment media seem misdirected. To judge from other research, television has improved its competitive edge versus the press by upgrading its public affairs programming, which is to say by becoming more like the newspaper.2' The main individual selfconstraint on newspaper use that we have identified here has been a lack of interest in politics and public affairs. Ironically, the newspaper's traditional 'watchdog" stance, which stresses the negative side of politics and government, may be inadvertently selfdefeating by breeding a general cynicism toward the world of politics. It is noteworthy that the recent era of declining newspaper readership has seen a parallel decline in public confidence in political leaders and parties, governmental institutions and democratic processes.% We have attempted in this paper to establish a framework for more comprehensive studies designed to examine a wider range of structural, transitional and self-constraint factors. We have focused on public affairs and politics, plus a few simple demographic variables, because those were the measures available from the national election studies. Research directed toward systematic analysis of newspaper reading in the context of structural barriers, lifecycle transitions and personal motivations would obviously go well beyond these few indicators. The attractions of different kinds of newspaper content for specific sub-audiencee, the role of other media and the place of the newspaper in changing lifestyles can all be approached from a constraints perspective. A fuller understanding of transitional constraints would require more longitudinal studies over longer periods with more than two waves of measurement.</p><p>Although a simple media-compbition model does not appear to account for declining newspaper readership, new generations of young people coming of age in a world of expanding media choice are distinctly less likely than their predecessors to adopt newspaper reading as a part of daily life. Socialization to media habits deserves much more careful rarearch attention a s new communication technologies proliferate and strudural constraints recede.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>FIGURE ITheoretical Relationships Among Constraints on Newspaper Reading rURAL LAINTS</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>2'</head><label></label><figDesc>Although Figure I m y appear t o lend itself t o testing by path analysis or other multiple r e g a r i o n models. the dependent variable (readership status) is i typology rather than a single dimension of variation.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>21</head><label></label><figDesc>Robinson and Jcffrcs. op. ci:,, In. I , pp. 18-20, Tipton. op. cil., fn. 6. "Thaefunctiom arederived byaprocedurein whichthelint function separates the four group as much u possible; 8iven this separation. the second function rcparates them as much as possible in a dimtion orthogonal to the fin1 function; then the third function provides maximal wparation in another onhogor ~l direction. This nukes the four groups as distinct u possible. in terms of the original discriminating variables entered.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>3'</head><label></label><figDesc>L m eOprC. 'How the Clulkn#e of Tdcvhwn N m Affsu the Rolpcrily of h i l y Newxplpm," JOURNALISM QUAR-TERLY, 5240MIO (Autumn 1979). =Robinson d JCam, op. dl.. fn. 1. *Artbur H. M i l k . "Polilia1 Iuva id TIUII in Govna-</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Donna Wilson, "Mass Communication in Politiul Socializa- tion," in Stanley Renshon (cd.). Handbook of Political Commu- nication (New York: Frcc Press</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note><p>. 1977). pp. 223-258. *Lonard P. Tipton. "</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>ANPA Newspaper Readership Stud- ies." ANPA NCWJ Research Report No. 13 (July. 1978). ' From 1940 to 1970. the median eduution of adult Amcri- cans rose from 8.6yean to 12.2yun.andthepercenugeofhigh school graduales in the adult population grew from 57.4% to 75.6%. Bureau of the Census. Historical Statistics of thr United Siaie5 (Washinglon: U.S. Government Printing Office. 1975</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note><p><p>).</p>I Recent</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>UNESCO figures Iht ninecountria in Afriu with no daily newspapers, and in ten Asian and Middle Eutern coun- tries newspaper circulation is less than 20 per 1.ooO population. In most Latin Ameriuncounlries thefigureis below IOOcircula- tion per 1.ooO population. ranging from 27 in Guatemala to 269 in Uruguay. World Communication (New York: UNESCO, 1975</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note><p>). *Keith R . Stamm. Kenneth M.</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Jackson and Lawrena Bowen. "Newspaper Uac Among New Residents," ANPA News</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>10 Lowndes F. Stephens. "The Influence of Community Att- achment on Newpaper Reading Habits." ANPA NCWS Rcsmrch Reporf No. /7(Dcrrmber. 1978). McLeod andChoe. op. cif.. fn. 3. 11 Much reant motivational work has focused on positive attractions bawd on the 'gratifications" provided by medu "uses." Thew studies have frequently d u l l with political topics. often in election settings. Exampla are Jack M. McLeod and Lec B. k k e r . 'Testing the Validity of Gratifications Measures Through Politicnl Effects Analysis." in Jay G. Blumlcr and Elihu Katz (cds.), The Uscr of M a r Communicurion (Beverly Hills: Sage. 1974). pp. 137-164. Lee B. kcker. "Two Tau of Media Gratifications: Watergate and the I974 Election." JOURNAL- ISM QUARTERLY 53:28-33,87 (Spring. 1976). Steven H. C h f - fee and Fausto Izuray. 'Maw Communication Functions in a Media-Rich Developing Society," Communicarion Rrsmrrh. 2367-395 (October. 1975).</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>11 Sidney Verb. and Nornun H. Nie. Parriciprrrionin Amrrica (New York: Harper and Row, 1972). Richard L. Allen and Steven H. Chaffcc, 'Mau Communication and the Political Participation of Black Americans." Communirarion Yrwbwk 3 (New Brunswick. N.J.: Tranuction Books. 1979). pp. 507-522 11 Warren E. Miller. Arthur H. Miller and F. Gerald Kline. 7hr CPS 1974 Amrrican Narional Elrcrion Srudy(Ann Arbor: Inter-University Consortium for Political and Social Ruearch, 1975). Warren E. Miller and Arthur H. Miller. 7he CPS 1976 Amrricun Nurional Elrrrion Srudv (Ann Arbor: Inter-Unlver- sity Consortium for Political and Social Research. 1977)</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>In each year,</cell></row><row><cell>large representative cross-sectional sam-</cell></row><row><cell>ples of adult Americans were interviewed:</cell></row><row><cell>1,575 persons in 1974, and 2,248 in 1976.</cell></row><row><cell>Of those, 1,201 were interviewed in both</cell></row><row><cell>years; it is this subset that comprises the</cell></row><row><cell>panel for our study.</cell></row><row><cell>Readinggroups. Breakdown of the sam-</cell></row><row><cell>ple into the four readership status groups</cell></row><row><cell>was based on a single question, asked in</cell></row><row><cell>both 1974 and 1976: "Do you read a daily</cell></row><row><cell>newspaper?" Those who answered "yes" at</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>TABLE 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Reading Daily Newspaper,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>1974 vs. 1976</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>1974</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>1976</cell><cell>Don't Read</cell><cell>Read</cell></row><row><cell>Don't</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Read</cell><cell>19.5%</cell><cell>6.0%</cell></row><row><cell>Read</cell><cell>8.2%</cell><cell>66.3%</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>N= 1 .@I6</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">both times were classified as stable readers,</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">and those who answered ''no" both times</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">as stable non-readers. The droppers were</cell></row></table><note><p>people who said "yes" in 1974 but "no" in 1976, while adders answered "no" in 1974 but "yes" in 1976. Approximately 91% of the panel respondents were asked this question and answered it yes or no, in both years; only these cases are classifiable for our analysis (N= 1,096).</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>to have increased. from 72% in 1974 to 74% in 1976. The</head><label></label><figDesc>more representative cross-sectional data indicate otherwise. however: in the full 1974 sample 73% were newspaper readers. but in 1976 this figure had dropped to 71%. T h c x figures are similar to thole reported by other national survey agencies. cited in Robinson and Jcffres. op. cil.. fn. I . T o judge from the care with which CPS sampling and interviewing arc conducted, and from the small deviation (+Z%) ofthe panel data from the cross-sectional waves. the droppers and adders In this panel can probably bc taken as reasonably reprtsentrtive of the much larger populations of newspaper droppers and adders nationwide. Chaflce and Donna Wilson, 'Adult Life-Cycle Change in M a s Media Use." pmentcd to Association for Education in Journalism. Ottawa. Canada, August 1975.</figDesc><table /><note><p>15 Steven H.</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>to vote for a</head><label></label><figDesc>candidate. The attention measure was. 'Some people seem to follow what's going on in government and public affairs most of the time. whether there's an election going on or not. OChcn aren't that interested. Would you say you follow what's going on in government and public affain most of the lime. some of the time. only now and then. or hardly at ill?" I'Thc items included writingalcttcrtothecditoronalocal. or national. problem; joining an organization working on a local. or national. problem; joining in a demonstration regarding a local. or national. problem; signing a petition on a local. or national problem: contacting a local or national public official; and attending a city council or school board mecting.</figDesc><table><row><cell>1.</cell><cell>StcLcn H. Chalice. "Political In\ol\crncnt and hcv\pa-</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">per Rcading." procntcd to Aiwciauon for Education In</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Journalirrn. Howton. Tcxa,. Augu\t 1919</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">'8Campaign activity items were attending a politicdl rally or</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">meeting; working for a candidate o r party; displaying a u m -</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">paign button or bumper sticker; and trying t o influence someone</cell></row><row><cell>clsc</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>TABLE 2 Indicators of Constraint, by Reading Group (Entries are means, with standard deviations in parentheses) Measure (year measured) Education (1976) Income (1976) Age (1976) Changed residence (1974 to 1976) Changed marital status (1974 to 1976) Changed employment status (1974 to 1976) Attention to public affairs (1974 + 1976) Political activity (1976) Campaign interest (1974 + 1976) Campaign activity (1974 + 1976) (Group N)</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Table 2 have been entered in the multiple discriminant analysis (Table 3). Of the three possible functions that could discriminate among the four groups, two are statistically significant.23 Table 3 describes each function in terms of two different coefficients. The first is the zero-order correlation between Changed employment status</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>.I6</cell><cell>-.21</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-. 10</cell><cell>.38</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>.25</cell><cell>.I7</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-.06</cell><cell>.45</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-.06</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>.02</cell><cell></cell><cell>-.22</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>-.21</cell><cell></cell><cell>.I3</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>.01 .04 .37 .05</cell><cell>.07 .23 .06</cell><cell>El -.42</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>.72</cell><cell>-.23</cell><cell>-.44</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>.36 .09</cell><cell>-. 10 .I6</cell><cell>.20 .oo</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>. I I</cell><cell>.04</cell><cell>.23</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>.26</cell><cell>.08</cell><cell>.05</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>-.I3</cell><cell>.89</cell><cell>-.01</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>-.04</cell><cell>-.I2</cell><cell>.01</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>-.Ol</cell><cell>.20</cell><cell>.21</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>.03 -.oo</cell><cell>-.04 .24</cell><cell>-.58 .45</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>.09</cell><cell>-.02</cell><cell>-.37</cell></row><row><cell>Canonical Correlation</cell><cell>.41</cell><cell>.20</cell><cell>. I I</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(P&lt;.OO1)</cell><cell>(P&lt;.OOI)</cell><cell>(n.s.)</cell></row><row><cell>Eigenvalue</cell><cell>.20</cell><cell>.04</cell><cell>.01</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12"><head>TABLE 4 Canonical Discriminant Function Centroids of the Four Groups Function 1 Function 2 Function 3</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-.75</cell><cell>t.02</cell><cell>-.08</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-.28</cell><cell>+.41</cell><cell>-.71</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-.27</cell><cell>+.55</cell><cell>-.w</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>+.28</cell><cell>-. I 1</cell><cell>+. 10</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>TABLE 5</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Reading of Soft and Hard News, Stable Readers vs. Droppers 1974</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(Cell entries are means)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Unweiphted</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Droppers</cell><cell cols="2">Stable readers</cell><cell>Row mean</cell></row><row><cell>Soft news reading</cell><cell>9.06</cell><cell>9.68</cell><cell></cell><cell>9.37</cell></row><row><cell>Hard news reading</cell><cell>8.26</cell><cell>9.81</cell><cell></cell><cell>9.04</cell></row><row><cell>Column mean</cell><cell>8.66</cell><cell>9.75</cell><cell></cell><cell>9.20</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_13"><head>Droppers vs. Readers, F=33.02 (dfz1.790). p&lt;.OOI Soft vs. Hard News Reading, F=5.11 (df=1.790), p&lt;.02 Interaction, Groups by Content, F.10.01 (df=1,790), p&lt;.OO2</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_14"><head>TABLE 6 Reading of Soft and Hard News, Stable, Readers vs. Adders 1976 (Cell entries are means)</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Unweighted</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Adders</cell><cell>Stable readers</cell><cell>Row mean</cell></row><row><cell>Soft news reading</cell><cell>8.60</cell><cell>9.42</cell><cell>9.01</cell></row><row><cell>Hard news reading</cell><cell>8.73</cell><cell>9.56</cell><cell>9. I5</cell></row><row><cell>Column mean</cell><cell>8.66</cell><cell>9.49</cell><cell>9.08</cell></row><row><cell>Adders vs. Readers. F=24.95 (dfz1.814). p&lt;.Ool)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Soft vs. Hard News Reading, F=1.00 (df=1,814), n.s.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Interaction, Group by Contents, F=O (df=1,814), n.s.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>discriminant analysis. To examine self-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>constraints separately, we turn to consider-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>ation of the groups that were reading</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>newspapers at a given time and can there-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>fore be assumed not to have been especially</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>constrained either structurally or transi-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>tionally.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Reading soft vs. hard news. Central to</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>consideration of self-constraints as deter-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>minants of newspaper use is the question of</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>what kinds of news the person reads. To</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>the extent that self-constraints operate on</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>news selection within the newspaper, they</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>should reduce the frequency of reading</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>"hard news" stories, but should not affect</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>reading of other kinds of content, which</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_0"><p>at UCSF LIBRARY &amp; CKM on March 23, 2015 jmq.sagepub.com Downloaded from</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>STRUCI CONSTR 1</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Non-readers</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Droppers</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Adders</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Readers</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
